Victor Apaez | Software Engineer



Software Engineer with experience in management, eager to bring forward innovative and creative solutions to improve the way we interact with technology. Proven to be a leader, team player, and reliable worker with three years of experience managing an E-commerce team. I am excited about the opportunity to bring my skills and experience to a new organization and contribute to its success.

SKILLS

- Languages: JavaScript, HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, Python, SQL
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, | Other: RESTful Routing, JSON API
- Libraries/Frameworks: React, Express.js, Node.js

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

League of Legends | FE - Github | BE - Github | Live Demo

Nov 2022 - Present

With over 117 million monthly users on League of Legends, this web application helps gamers search and build teams with their favorite characters and items.

- Managed a team of 5 developers to create a full-stack web application with MERN stack (MongoDb, Express.js, React.js, and Node.js).
- Directed team standup meetings to communicate on progress and plan code direction.
- Built out full CRUD (create, read, update, delete) operations hitting all RESTful API calls.
- Tested API routes using Postman to ensure functionality during production.
- Implemented user authentication using json web token and bcrypt on the server.

Breddit | FE - Github | BE - Github | Chat BE - Github | Live Demo

Dec 2022 - Present

Inspired by Reddit, this web application is a network of communities where people can share their interests and ideas.

- Collaborated with a team of 10 developers to create Better Reddit using React.js, Django, and Express.js.
- Delegated features to team members and assisted with debugging.
- Achieved a viable product with over 450 commits in 5 days using feature branch workflow.
- Designed a chat server to establish a WebSocket connection using socket.io.
- Applied socket.io on the front end using React.js to send messages between users.

Trailers App | Github | Live Demo

Oct 2022 - Present

A Netflix replica, this web application has trailers for top rated, now playing, and current entertainment.

- Engineered a responsive web application for watching trailers using best practices with React.js, Styled-components and CSS3 flexbox layout.
- Implemented The Movie DB API to fetch live film and tv series data.
- Utilized the IFrame Player API and The Movie DB API to display video trailers on the website by fetching the necessary keys for the videos.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Fellow | General Assembly | New york, NY

Sept 2022 - Dec 2022

- Completed over 400 hours of professional training in a 12-week program, gaining hands-on experience in designing and building web applications with full CRUD functionality using technologies such as JavaScript, React, Express, MongoDB, HTML, and CSS.
- Key skills: Object oriented programming (OOP), responsive, scalable, web development

Manager | Rubber Stamp Creation | Brooklyn, NY

Nov 2019 – Aug 2022

- Researched and hired 20+ new employees for the department, providing training and delegating responsibilities
 to the most qualified individuals based on their skills and experience. Enforced company policies and procedures
 to ensure compliance and efficiency.
- Managed the day-to-day operations of a team of 20+ employees, setting performance goals and ensuring their completion within specific timeframes. Ensured compliance with company standards, specifications, guidelines, training, and cultural values.
- Key skills: communication, conflict resolution, time management, leadership, teamwork

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive | New York, NY New York City College of Technology - A.S. Computer Science: Completed 70 credits

Sept 2022 – Dec 2022 Fall 2014 – Spring 2017